RAGHAV AGGARWAL

+91-7042266811 • raghavaggarwal200004@gmail.com • GitHub • LinkedIn • Leetcode

PROFILE SUMMARY

Technology-driven Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in translating business requirements and functional specification into code modules and innovative solutions. Deep understanding of Software Development Life Cycle and Innovative Technologies such as, full stack Mobile and Web Applications and Chat-bot development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Plutos One(Fintech)

Sept 2023 – Present

Software Developer Engineer

- 1. Created **WhatsApp Chatbot** and Web Chatbot using **React and Python** (Rasa and Llama Index) from scratch having **15+ different languages** using **Google API, Bhasini** and actively used by **1 Lacs+ users.**
- 2. Creation of TSP(Technology service providers) & SaaS(Software as a service) for banks and worked with NPCI (National Payment Corporation of India) and enabled their users to pay their bills hassle free.
- 3. Implementation of **BBPS GPT** (Generative Pre-trained Transformer) for bill payments.
- 4. Development of script which can automatically translate languages in App Scripts(MS Excel)
- 5. Created Software Solutions for VISA, BOB, IDBI, etc

Blocktickets.io

June 2022 - Aug 2023

Full Stack Developer

- 1. Launched Back-end where users can purchase tickets from the platform using Node.JS and MongoDB
- 2. Managed the integration and deployment of the application with **React** frontend.
- 3. Responsible for **System design** and creating an optimized and clean **Restful** backend application.

SKILLS

- Languages: C, C++, JavaScript, Python
- Frameworks and Tools: Nodejs, express.JS, React.JS Django, Rasa, Ollama
- Other Skills: DSA, Redux, AWS, GitHub(Version Control), Git, MySQL, Socket.io, Postman, BullMq, Postgresql, Docker-compose, Websockets, Responsive Web Design, Jest, Agile Methodologies, Database Querying
- Non-Technical Skills: Team work, Collaboration, Communication, Adaptability and Multi-tasking, Innovative

PROJECTS

Plutos ONE Chatbot (Skills: Rasa, Python, Django React.JS)

Dec 2023 -Present

- 1. Developed an efficient and stable Web chatbot using Rasa and Django.
- 2. Created Whatsapp chatbot using GupShup API for communication between server and WhatsApp
- 3. Implemented Openhermes LLM for semantic search
- 4. Responsible for sync operations into **Redis** using valid **Data structures** for faster API response.

Blocktickets Back-end (Skills: Node.JS, MongoDB, JavaScript, S3, EC2)

Mar 2023 – Aug 2023

- 1. Developed API's for ticket selling platform and admin panel for the events' upgrade and order management.
- 2. Integrated with Cloud APIs and Nodemailer for sending ticket information and verification as well as "Cashfree" for payments.
- 3. Utilized cloud-based AWS EC2 to deploy the back-end code, S3 for image upload.

Live chat Application (Skills: MERN, JWT, Socket.io, Cloudinary, Chakra UI, CSS)

Jan 2022 - May 2022

- 1. **Socket rooms** are created for multiple connection
- 2. Implemented **Chakra UI** to create a responsive and interactive application
- 3. Operated Cloudinary to upload images(GitHub) (Deployment)

E-commerce Website (Skills: Node.JS, MongoDB, EJS, Html, JWT Es6)

Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

- 1. Developed an infrastructure for sellers and buyers.
- 2. Used Jasmine for writing Unit Test cases.
- 3. Ensured proper Encryption of passwords, secure and robust web app. (GitHub) (Deployment)

Rate Limiter Middleware (Skills: Node.JS, cookies)

July 2021 – July 2021

- 1. Created a middleware which can be used by anyone.
- 2. Enhanced security, as an IP address can access the API for n (as per developer/business) time only.(GitHub)

EDUCATION

Galgotias College of Engineering and Technology affiliated to AKTU

Master's Degree in Computer Application Development (MCA)

Jagannath Institute of Management Studies affiliated to IPU

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (BCA)

Nov 2021 – June 2023

Percentage: 74

July 2018 – May 2021

Percentage: 80.5